The first step in the expectation maximization algorithm for
用于 GMM 聚类的期望最大化算法的第一步是
doing GMM clustering is to initialize the Gaussian distributions.
初始化高斯分布
In this example, we have two Gaussian distributions,
在本例中 我们有两个高斯分布
so we need to give them initial values.
我们要为其赋初始值
Basically, we need to give them a mean and a standard deviation for each of the two.
基本上 我们需要给它们均值和标准差
So there are a few ways to do that.
有很多方法可以做到这一点
The naive way to do it is to just set them to the average and mean of the dataset itself.
朴素的方法是将它们设置为数据集本身的平均值
So, that's one way to do it.
这是一种方法
In practice, however, a better way to do that is to run k-means on the dataset,
但在实践中还有一种更好的方法 是在数据集上使用 k 均值
and then we can use the clusters produced by
然后我们可以使用由 k 均值生成的聚类
k-means to initialize the Gaussian distributions.
初始化高斯分布
For this example here,
但在这个例子中
however, let's pick random points,
我们选取任意点
a random mean for each of the two Gaussians and a random variance.
为每个高斯选择随机均值和随机方差
So we're going to be talking,
所以我们将要讲的
instead of standard deviation,
不是标准差
we'll be talking about variance.
而是方差
And variance is simply the standard deviation squared.
方差就是标准差的平方
And so these are the two Gaussians that we have,
这就是我们的两个高斯模型
each with its own center and its own variance.
它们每个都有自己的中心和方差
We're still graphing the standard deviations here,
我们仍在绘制这里的标准偏差
but the calculations all talk about variance rather than the standard deviation.
但是所有的计算都谈论的是方差而不是标准差
And with this, the first step is done,
这样我们就完成了第一步
and now, we have two Gaussians.
现在我们可以对这两个高斯分布
We can proceed to step two.
进行第二步了
Step two is to do a soft clustering of the data points.
第二步是对数据集进行软聚类
This is called the expectation step.
这步称为期望步骤
Basically, this is our dataset.
这是我们的数据集
So we have N points.
有 N 个点
Each one has these two values for each feature.
每个点都有这两个值
And so we have to calculate the membership of each point to each cluster.
因此 我们必须计算每个点对每个聚类的隶属度
And this is not impossible.
这是有可能的
We can intuitively look at a point like this and say that it's more
比如说 我们可以直观地将一个点看成这样
likely that it came from this Gaussian rather than this Gaussian,
并且认为它更可能来自这个高斯 而不是那个高斯
just because it's closer.
因为它们更接近
But there is a way to actually calculate a number for that,
但有一种方法可以为此计算出一个值
and it looks a little bit like this.
这就是计算公式
This is basically the probability density function of a normal distribution.
这基本上是正态分布的概率密度函数
This is where we can really benefit from what we know from statistics
这才是我们可以真正从我们所知的高斯分布和正态分布的统计和概率中
and probability about Gaussian and normal distributions.
获益的地方
This is a term we can calculate,
这是一个可以计算的项
and this here is the same term as this,
这个和上个一样
and this is slightly different.
这个稍微有点不同
So these are given the first Gaussian,
因此 这些是关于第一个高斯的项
and these are given the second Gaussian.
而这些是有关第二个高斯的项
To clarify this, let's take an example.
为了进一步解释 我们举个例子
Let's look at the first point here.
我们先看一些这里的第一个点
This is where it lies.
这是其所处的位置
So, we can first intuitively say that it's most
所以 我们起初可以直观的说这个点
likely that it came from Gaussian A rather than Gaussian B.
很可能来自高斯 A 而非高斯 B
So it belongs to Cluster A more than it does Cluster B.
因此 这个点更可能属于聚类 A 而非聚类 B
But let's go through the calculation and see
但让我们进行计算
what number we will assign the membership of it to.
看看它们的隶属度到底是多少
And so, the membership of point number one to
所以 点一到聚类 A 的隶属度
Cluster A is denoted by E or the expectation of Z1a.
可以表示为 E 或 Z1A 的期望
So 1 is the number of number of point,
其中 1 表示点一
A is the name of the cluster,
A 表示聚类
Z is what is called a hidden variable or a latent variable.
Z 是所谓的隐藏变量或潜在变量
There are very clever mathematical trick that enable us to do all of this.
我们可以利用非常聪明的数学技巧做到这一切
We will not discuss Z and what Z does and how Z was used
我们不会讨论 Z 的作用以及如何用 Z 推导这个
to derive this here because we want to look at an oversimplified example.
因为我们希望这是个非常简单的例子
So let's proceed to plug in X1,
这里的这个点
so this point here,
是在给定的高斯 A 或群类 A 的参数下把 X1
into this probability density function given the parameters of Gaussian A or Cluster A.
插入这个概率密度函数
This is the probability density function of a normal distribution.
这是正态分布的概率密度函数
So we just plug in X here,
所以我们在这里插入 X
and we plug in the parameters of the Gaussian A here,
我们在这里插入高斯 A 的参数
and that would come up with a number,
这个算式会计算出一个值
and that number is 0.001288.
为 0.001288
So we put that here and here,
我们把这个值代入这里和这里
and we do the same by plugging in X, this point X,
同样 我们把点 X 插入概率密度函数给定的
into the probability density function given the parameters of
第二个聚类 B 或高斯 B 的
the second of Cluster B or the Gaussian B,
第二个参数
and that gives us this value here.
来得到这个值
And so this is simple calculation.
这是比较简单的计算
It turns out to be 0.99976.
结果为 0.99976
And what this means is that we are
这意味着
99.97 percent sure that this point belongs to this cluster here.
我们 99.97% 的确定这个点属于聚类 A
And so that is the membership of point number 1 to Cluster A.
所以这是点一对聚类 A 的隶属度
From here, we can simply calculate its membership to cluster
从这里 我们可以简单地计算出点一对聚类 B 的隶属度
B since this value is between 0 and 1.
因为这个值在 0 和 1 之间
So to calculate Cluster B membership is just 1 minus this value,
所以 点一对聚类 B 的隶属度为 1-0.99976
or we can just plug it in to the same formula
或者我们也可以将其代入同一个算式
but to the different clusters and derive the same value here,
只是不同的聚类 但结果一样
especially if we have more than two clusters.
尤其是当我们有多个聚类时
And so this is the soft clustering of point number 1 with
因此 这就是我们在第一步初始化的
regards to Cluster A and Cluster B that we initialize in the first step.
关于聚类 A 和聚类 B 的点一的软聚类
And so if we fill up the rest of these two columns,
因此 如果我们计算这里每个点对每个聚类的隶属度
calculating the membership to each cluster for each point,
将其结果填写在这两列
we end up with something that looks like this.
结果就是这样
And let's take a closer look at this.
让我们再进一步来看看
So all of these red points have the highest membership with Cluster A.
因此 所有这些红点都与聚类 A 的隶属度最高
And all of these green points have the highest membership with Cluster B.
所有这些绿点都与聚类 B 的隶属度最高
And the points in the middle are probably
中间的这些点对聚类 A 或聚类 B 的隶属度
50-50 or 40-60 membership between the two clusters.
可能为 50-50 或 40-60
And with this, we have completed our soft clustering in step two,
这样我们就完成了我们的第二步的软聚类
and so we're ready to go to step three.
接着我们进行第三步
In step three, we will use this soft clustering to estimate new Gaussians.
在第三步 我们将利用这个软聚类来估计新的高斯模型
And that's what we'll look at in the next video.
我们将在下个视频中继续讲解